If you were a mad scientist trying to
create life in a lab, how would you do
it? One way to start is with something
already alive. So, you take something
like a bacterium and you download its
DNA and you make a few changes and then
you rebuild your new DNA in a lab and
then you insert it into a host, one that
already has the rest of the machinery
but no instructions. And once inside
your new DNA takes over, creating new
life, sort of cuz it kind of seems like
cheating to use an already living cell.
To really create life, you need to start
with something that's not alive. And
scientists just did exactly that. And
they made this guy. This is spud cell.
They made it entirely of chemicals. No
host cell, nothing like that. And today
it can do a lot of the things that
living cells can do, like eat and grow
and reproduce. But its DNA sequence is
tiny, way smaller than living bacteria,
which means that it still needs a lot of
help from scientists to keep going. And
it tends to fail after about 5 or 10
generations. So scientists say it's not
quite life in a lab yet. But they did
discover new life under Antarctica. So
to see that subscribe.